本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
Zatoh...
ザトウさん
Long time no see, Mr. Monster.
久しいの　怪物君
Wh-What are you talking about? "Monster"?
どういうことです　ミンスさん　怪物って？
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
That's the real Zatoh,
こいつは本物のザトウじゃ
お前とさっきまで一緒におったやつは違う
different from the man you
were with up till now.
What?
His name is Enlike Bishile,
奴の名はエンリケ＝ビスハイル
a pathetic kid who failed
to become a monster.
怪物になり損なった惨めな小僧さ
止まる者　愚かなりし
Todomaru mono oroka narishi
はらりひらり指に触れた黒い翼の　一片
Harari hirari yubi ni fureta
kuroi tsubasa no hitohira
诸
神字幕组
君が一つの　物語なら
Kimi ga hitotsu no monogatari nara
まだいくらでも　掛け替えられる
Mada ikura demo kakikaerareru
血のインクは乾かない
Chi no inku wa kawakanai
誰も知らない　本との僕ら
Dare mo shiranai hontou no bokura
荒れた世界　枯れるのは
Areta sekai kaeru no wa
追い求めたのは　ちっぽけな幸福なんかじゃない
Oimotometa no wa
Chippoke na koufuku nanka ja nai
戦え　轟く　音を合図に
Tatakae todoroku kodou wo aizu ni
意のまま　進めば
Inomama susumeba yukusaki hatenai
行く先　果てない
抗え　のたうち
Aragae notauchi ikudo to yaburedo
幾度と　汚れと
膝を纏った傷跡に夢を
Kizamou matotta kizuato ni yume wo
埋もれそうな今日の記憶繋げるために　明日へ
Umoresou na kyo no kioku
tsunageru tame ni ashita e
Episode 8
A Pond, Comrades, and a Seashell
第8话 沼泽
与
同伴
和
海边的贝壳
What are your thoughts?
如何でしょう？
It's fascinating.
面白いね
A kid who tried to become a monster...
怪物になろうとした小僧か？
Yes. Fascinating, indeed.
うん　面白い
But you don't need to read it.
しかしわざわざ読まなくとも　あなた様の力を使えば…
Why don't you just use your power?
Reading them is fun, too.
「本」を読むってのもまた面白い
Doing the same thing over and over...
Honestly, you grow tired of it.
同じばかりの繰り返しじゃ　正直飽きる
Enlike Bishile, wielding thunder.
エンリケ＝ビスハイルは　雷を操る
Wielding even more powerful thunder.
今よりも強い雷を操る
Enlike Bishile, wielding even more powerful
thunder with still greater precision.
エンリケ＝ビスハイルは　雷を操る
今よりもっと強く　もっと精密に
Enlike, you've been looking
so beleaguered lately.
エンリケ　近頃調子を崩してるようだが
Qumola.
クモラ
Huh?
Why doesn't Qumola smile?
クモラはなぜ笑わない？
She's a rat. Throw her some
food, and she'll smile.
あれはねずみだ　餌を貰えば笑うに決まってるんだ
Did you become sexually aware, too?
色気づいたか　貴様が
It's not ready yet?
まだかよ？
Not yet, but almost!
はい　もうちょっとなので
It's okay, Qumola.
大丈夫だ　クモラ
I'll protect you.
お前は俺が守る
Sasali?
ササリさん？
It's you and me tonight.
今夜　お前と俺だ
I've been waiting for this day.
この日を楽しみにしてた
Qumola will be delighted
to hear of your death.
お前が死ねばクモラも喜ぶ
Why?
なぜ？
Why? You know the answer!
知ってるだろう　クモラがお前を怖がってるのは
She's afraid of you!
Begin!
始め！
Aren't you gonna discharge that thunder
you always brag about?
撃たないのか？　自慢の雷を
This is revenge for my fallen brothers!
仲間たちの仇だ
思い知れ！
Damn!
しまっ…
Qumola...
クモラ
はっ　悪運も強い奴だ
He's got the devil's luck.
Still, he probably made for
some much-needed medicine.
まぁ　いい薬にはなったのが
Struggling against such a weak opponent...
この程度の相手にてこずるようでは
What happened after I passed out?
俺は　あれから…
I'm going to apply some
medicine to your back.
お背中を　薬を塗りますから
But my back wasn't hurt that...
そこは　あまり怪我して…
You just can't feel it. Now, please hurry.
気付いてないだけです
さぁ　早く
Enlike...
エンリケさん　五人目ですね
That makes five people.
Congratulations. Are you happy,
おめでとうございます
嬉しいですか　戦って勝つのは？
having won?
I'm not sure.
分からない
Why not? Don't you enjoy it?
なぜです？　お好きなんでしょう？
Doing that to others...
皆さんをああするのが
Not me.
いやだ　もう殺すのはいやだ
I'm sick of killing.
I kill and kill... It's no fun for me at all.
殺しても　殺しても　楽しくなんかなかった
I've never been able to smile.
笑えたことなんか　一度も…
They taught us that killing is fun.
殺すことが楽しいと教わった
I used to think it would be, too.
俺も　楽しいはずだと思っていた
But now...
でも　もう…
It's cruel... To say that... Now...
ひどい　そんな　今さら…
Do you really hate me that much?
そんなに俺を憎んでいるのか？
Please die, Enlike.
死んでください　エンリケさん
Each time someone dies, a sorrow comes
over me and I feel like dying myself.
誰かが死ぬたび　私も死にたいくらい悲しくなるんです
But I fight through it and survive.
でも我慢して生きて　まだ誰かが死んで苦して…
Then someone else dies, the sorrow
returns, and yet I still live on...
それでも　また生きてる
Qumola, I...
クモラ　俺は…
Five people have died already!
もう五人も死んだ
And my heart has died five
times with them...
私の心だって　もう五回も…
Even you, Enlike... You...
エンリケさんだって　一度くらい…し、死んだって
You could die too!
What's going on?
何事だ？
Boramotte. Let's stop doing this!
ポラモット　もうやめよう
What?
なんだと？
Please let me stop.
I can't take any more.
もうやめさせてくれ　無理なんだ　俺は
I...
You shut your mouth!
黙れ！
That dirty vermin planted some
weird idea in your mind, didn't she?
あのメスねずみになにか吹き込まれたかな
If Master Ganbanzel saw the
pathetic state of things...
もしガンバンゼル様にこの体たらくが知りたら…
That's it! I'm going to Heaven!
俺は行くぞ　天国に
Wait!
待って
Leave him be, Enlike.
もうよい　エンリケ
Ganbanzel.
ガンバルゼル
You'll never become a monster.
お前は所詮　怪物になどなれん
ハミュッツ＝メセタの笑顔を拒んだあの日から
The day you rejected Hamyuts Meseta's
smile set all this in motion.
すべてはこうなると決まっておった
You're a thunder-wielding fool,
汝は雷の愚者　ただ一つに焦がれ　ただ一つを得られる
yearning for one thing alone,
but never able to get it.
ならばせめて　すべてを同じく焼き尽くすが良い
At the very least, burn through it all,
be it without meaning to you!
Those idiots...
愚かな奴ら
Throwing their lives away for a lousy rat!
あんなねずみ一匹のために命を捨てるとは
Kayas...
カヤス
Enlike, I'm giving you one last chance.
エンリケ　最後の機会を
Go find Qumola and kill her.
クモラを探し出して　殺せ
Do that and...
そしたら…
I...
俺は…
Welcome back. Welcome back.
お疲れ様　お疲れ様
Welcome back, everyone. Welcome back.
皆さん　お疲れ様　お疲れ様なのです
Welcome back. Welcome back.
お疲れ様　お疲れ様…
Qumola will probably never smile again.
Welcome back. Welcome back.
クモラは　二度と笑わないだろう
Because there's no one left here.
なぜなら　ここにはもう…誰もいないのだから
That was the life of Enlike Bishile.
それが奴　エンリケ＝ビスハイルの人生さ
He was completely helpless.
救われない小僧だよ　まったく
That's impossible...
そんな馬鹿な　だってあたし
I know I spoke with him.
確かに話しましたよ　エンリケさんと
Yes, I've heard.
あー　聞いてた
You can't talk to the dead!
死んだ人と話せるわけないじゃないですか？
You can read their Books,
but that's different.
「本」を読むだけならともかく
It's because of his power.
それが能力なんよ　奴の
What?
はい？
へへ　見た目より頭いいね　お前
You're not as dumb as you look.
I've only read about him.
わしも資料でしか知らんだが
I didn't think he could actually exist.
まさか実在するとは思わなかったが
They call him the "Book Eater."
人呼んで「本喰い」
That transparent hair of his
leaves no doubt in my mind!
奴の透明な髪の毛こそ真っ向ことなき証じゃ
Huh?
Seeing is believing, huh?
百聞は一見にしかず
That's Luimon's...
ルイモンさんの…
Watch closely, my dear Noloty.
よくご覧あれ　ノロティちゃん
Noloty...
ノロティ
Someone else has joined us.
また一人来たか？
Qumola...
クモラ
Book Eaters...
「本喰い」
Even I had only imagined them to be a myth.
その存在は私にとりましても不可侵ような謎にございます
They say that, true to the
name, they eat Books.
彼らは文字通り「本」を食う
He traps those in the Books he eats
in a separate realm inside his body.
食った「本」を体内に広がる胃空間へ取り込む
They call them the Nonentity Entrails.
その名は「仮想臓腑」
The soul of the person eaten
is a pitiable prisoner.
喰われた「本」の主は哀れ魂の虜
うーん　いい感じじゃない
I like the feel of that.
Uh, let's see... What was it again?
えーと　これはなんてだっけ？
Oh, right. That kid named
Ronkeny's power!
そう　ロンケニーとかいう餓鬼の力
魔法能力は本来一人に一つ
Each person can only contain
one magic power.
But he can use the powers
of each person he eats!
じゃが奴は食った「本」の主の力を自分のものにできる
And that's why...
じゃから
The monster who attacked the Library
commanded many different types of magic.
図書館を襲った怪物は　一遍にいくつもの魔法を使えた
And this is the power of the
aforementioned Enlike.
これは過のエンリケ君の力
It was hilarious.
傑作だったぜ
That boy's eyes were completely empty
when I arrived on the island.
俺があの島に着いた時　小僧すっかり空っぽ目をしてある
Those brats were only there to
become food for yours truly.
あの餓鬼ども　俺の餌になるためだけに生かされてきたのさ
All that "becoming a monster"
business was just lies.
怪物になれるなんて嘘っぱち吹き込まれて
Fool!
アホ
That power...
この力　ルイモンさんの…
That's Luimon's!
Damn you!
この
That huge Librarian...
このでかぶつ司書　武器は腕力だけじゃないか
The only "weapon" he had was strength.
That's enough! You can't stop him!
止せ　お前じゃ無理だ
Please stop talking!
I'm angry right now!
黙っててください
私今怒ってるんです　ものすごく
So angry!
Oh?
What did you do with Luimon and Enlike?
ルイモンさんを　エンリケさんをどうしたの？
They're gone now.
奴らはもう終わった　もう永遠に表に出ない
You'll never see them again!
You lie!
嘘だ！
Now, dear Noloty...
Don't be so hard on yourself.
なぁ　ノロティちゃん　そう邪見にするなよ
あんたはまさに俺の命の恩人だ
You saved my life.
Who the hell saved you?!
誰かお前なんか助けた
Noloty!
ノロティ
Qumola...
クモラ
I was inside him that day, too.
俺はあの日も奴の中にいた
This... This is Qumola's Book.
この「本」　クモラ
And that's...
こいつ確か…
Oh, I'm glad you're okay now.
良かった　元気になって
Let me see your face.
顔…
I'm glad. I was able to save the others.
嬉しい　仲間を助けられて
Glad...
嬉…しい
Don't make a sound.
声を出すな　ついて来い
Follow me.
逃げるんだ　船を奪って
I'm stealing a boat and getting out of here.
もう一秒だって　こんな所…
I can't spend one more second
in this hellhole.
I don't wanna die.
死にたくない
I want to save...
助け…たい
助けたいです…私…皆さんを
...everyone.
Qumola...
クモラ
Not me.
いやだ
I'm sick of killing.
もう殺すのはいやだ
I kill and kill... It's no fun for me at all.
殺しても　殺しても　楽しくなんかなかった
I've never been able to smile.
笑えたことなんか　一度も…
To say that now...
そんな　今さら…
I hated him so much before
that, but a monster...
憎み続けてきたのに　あの人は化け物だと
Why didn't you kill him, then?
じゃあ　なぜ殺さなかった？
Because...
あの人は…あの人は…
Because he may have killed many
people and injured others,
たくさん人を殺して　たくさん傷つけた
but he was still no different than you and I.
でも　それでもやっぱり　私たちと同じなんだと思います
So I want to save him.
助けたいです　私　あの人を
Then it's settled. Let's go!
決めた　行こう！
Huh?
We'll kill Boramotte and
take one of the ships!
ボラモットを倒して　船を奪うんだ
If we work together, we can do it!
皆で力を合わせれば　きっと何とかなる
We'll get off this island and live!
島を出て暮らすんだよ
You'll be fine, Qumola. We'll protect you.
大丈夫　クモラ　お前は俺たちが守って
What about Enlike?
エンリケさんは？
He'll come with us, of course.
一緒さ　もちろん
You said it yourself:
He's no different from you and I.
だって　あいつも同じなんだろう　私と
You traitors!
貴様ら
I...
俺は…
俺は！
Yes. I, Enlike Bishile,
俺　エンリケ＝ビスハイルは
commandeered this man, Zatoh's, body.
こうしてザトウの体を乗っ取った
I came to this town in search
of a place to die.
そして死に場所を探し　この街にやってきた
なのに…
But...
G-Give back... Enlike!
返せ　エンリケさんを
Damn it.
畜生　俺は…
I...
Giving up already, Enlike?
諦める気かい？　エンリケ
You'd better not even consider
being the only one to give up.
許さないぜ　お前一人諦めようだなんて
Guys...
お前ら…
Qumola came with us to rescue you.
クモラは　俺たちとお前を助けようとした
Relia showed you kindness. And now...
レーリアって奴は　お前に優しくしてくれた
そして　今戦ってるあの子は
The girl fighting outside...
...is putting her life on the line to save me.
命がけで　助けようとしてる　こんな俺を…
What do I do?
どうすればいい？
Think about it, dummy!
考えろ　馬鹿野郎
You'll search through every square inch
of this place for a way out!
てめえの手持ちを引っくり返して
血眼で探し出せ
Noloty!
ノロティ
T-Take a nap, will ya?
大人しく寝てろ
Minth?!
ミンスさん
Why not admit defeat like
a good girl, Noloty?
いい加減諦めたらどうだい　ノロティちゃん
He's dead, you know.
奴はもう死んだ
No.
違う
He's alive.
あの人は生きてる
Enlike's continuing to fight inside of you!
エンリケさんは　あなたの中で諦めずに戦ってる
はっ　負け惜しみかよ
Can't admit defeat, huh?
Farewell. I'll come find you
once you're a Book.
あばよ　「本」になったら　また会おう
Enlike?
エンリケさん？
Th-That's impossible!
そ、そんな馬鹿な
You aren't the only one who
can wield thunder, Zatoh Rondohoon.
雷を操るのは　ザトウ＝ロンドホーンではない
Enlike Bishile, wielding more powerful thunder,
with greater precision than ever before.
雷を操るのは　エンリケ＝ビスハイル
かつて　強く　精密に
See, you can do whatever
you put your mind to!
やればできるじゃねえか　くそったれ
Sasali?
ササリ
Let's do this, Enlike.
行きますよ　エンリケさん
Water, blast!
水弾よ　出ろ
Blast me, Enlike.
やれ　エンリケ
What?
なに？
Next!
次だ
What? What's going on?
なんじゃ　何か起こっとる？
Damn it!
畜生
Do it, Enlike.
やってくれ　エンリケ
Ronkeny...
ロンケニー
No.
ダメだ
You can't do that.
それはいけない
If you kill him, you'll die, too.
奴を殺せば　君も死ぬぞ
Don't worry about me.
いいんだ　俺は
We'll hold him back. Get out of here.
こいつは俺たちが抑える
お前は行け
Stop!
やめろ！
どうして俺を生かす？
Why are you letting me live?
We've had enough of you.
憂さ晴らしだよ
お前みたいないけすかない野郎は
You can be pretty disgusting.
Stop!
やめろ
Go live a long life.
生き延びちまえばいいんだ
Smile from ear to ear, like an idiot.
馬鹿みたいにへらへら笑って
Qumola.
クモラ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Noloty...
ノロティ
あっ　どっち？
Who are you now?
Don't cry sitting over me.
人の上で泣くな
I can handle the tears, but your
snot is dripping on me.
涙はともかく　鼻水まで落ちてくる
Enlike!
エンリケさん
You're heavy and in the way. Move.
邪魔だ　重い　どけ
Looks like you got a new lease on life.
生き延びてしまいましたね
This isn't the time to smile. Stop.
笑ってる場合ではない　笑うな
You stop first.
エンリケさんこそ…
A-Acting Director?!
代行
Nice job!
お疲れ
Were you watching everything?
For how long?
ずっと見とたんのか　いつから？
My, whatever are you speaking of?
えー　ミンスなに言ってるかな？
Don't play dumb.
せっ　惚けるじゃねぇ
Anyway, Acting Director,
にしても　代行　残念だったなぁ
it's a shame we weren't able
to fight the monster.
怪物と戦えなくてよ
Huh? Not at all.
えー　ぜーんぜん　だってさあ
I mean, we've got a worthy adversary...
相手ならいるでしょう？
Right there.
あそこに
Taiyo tojiru mae ni
Hikari wo nakushite
Mekurumeku arashi nara
Temaneku mae ni tobikomu
Dare mo itsuka owaru no deshou
Sono hi ga kureba
Mawaridasu mirai wo mezashite
Tada sore wa mou shirusarete ita to shitemo
Sagashidasu kizutsuku imi sae kono te ni
Jibunrashiku aru tame ni
A True Man,
A certain True Man desires Heaven.
ある「真人」の欲する天国
A True Man, a Battlefield,
A certain True Man desires Heaven.
The morning sun burns the
eye, as flowers wilt.
朝日は目を焼き　花は枯れ
Lightning illuminates the deformed
heart of a martyr, and then pierces.
雷は殉教者の歪な心根を手出し刺し
A True Man, a Battlefield, and My World
Lightning illuminates the deformed
heart of a martyr, and then pierces.
真人与战场和我的世界
Lightning illuminates the deformed
heart of a martyr, and then pierces.
そして　貫く